<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my portfolio page! on Evgenii Sinkov</title>
    <link>https://sinkov.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my portfolio page! on Evgenii Sinkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sinkov.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Natural Language Processing Classifier as a Feature for an Assistive Device</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo contains the full report in pdf, Jupyter notebooks and other supplementary files.
Abstract Since the emergence of AI and the recent increase in computational power of machines, the healthcare industry has quickly become one of the most forward-thinking fields of application. This work is intended to help the Rolls-Royce initiative in developing an assistive technology device for Motor Neuron Disease patients. This paper compares different Natural Language Processing and machine learning techniques for predicting the category of a user&amp;rsquo;s question using a publicly available dataset - Yahoo Answers, which contains ten categories and 1,4 million rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining whether the IMDB review was helpful using NLP frameworks</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo has the corresponding Jupyter notebook and beautiful report 😋.
Assignment description The final course project (FCP) consists of a text classification task: you’re supposed to adjudicate between helpful and unhelpful movie reviews from the IMDB database. For the sake of redundancy, your goal is to classify each movie review “i” into one of the two categories: 0/not helpful: less than 30% of IMDB users found movie review “i” helpful 1/helpful: more than 70% of IMDB users found movie review “i” helpful</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Commits Database Design &amp; Analysis</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo has the corresponding Jupyter Notebooks, SQL scripts and final report.
Assignment description For the final course project (fcp), you will handle a real-world dataset. In particular, you are required to store, manipulate, and analyze GitHub data for PyTorch and Tensorflow. Both projects are examples of open source software (OSS) development. OSS challenges common managerial assumptions on the organizing and func- tioning of organizations (Gulati et al., 2012), attracting the interest of research enthusiasts from several disciplines (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing Explanatory Data Analysis (EDL) and applying Machine Learning to the Kaggle dataset (Hotel bookings)</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo has the corresponding Jupyter notebook.
Have a look at the Kaggle Dataset
Some LSTM results for guests arrivals forecasting </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection for the wind turbine records using Recurrent Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo with the Jupyter notebook and raw data from sensors.
😋 As an appetizer have a look at some charts from the analysis!
Sensors data per second: Sensor 1 Sensor 2 Confusion marices visualization Task description Create a recurrent neural network in TensorFlow to predict the operating mode of a wind turbine based on the two time series from the sensors. Before any implementation, carefully consider what type of approach (sequence-to-vector, sequence-to-sequence, or encoder-decoder) is most sensible here and how you need to manipulate the data, given that you have two different time series for each observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive EDA and some customer segmentation for the supermarket clients</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>📂 The Github Repo contains Jupyter notebook and the raw dataset
Here are some of the most pretty charts 📊 Group coursework. Task description. •Please upload your reports inone pdf filewith no more than 5 pages long including plots, of which no more than 3 pages should be text.
•Please also upload the script for the analysis.
•This coursework will be assessed based on the quality of your report, e.g. presenta- tion, quality of plots, details about the experiment settings, motivations to use the methods, analysis of the results, conclusions etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying revenue management methods to the resort hotel Kapriz Issyk Kul</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The Github Repo contains presentation, raw historical data Python code with demand modelling and R code with all the tools.
Business context
Kapriz resort is the leading summer recreation centre in Central Asia, located in the heart of Kyrgyzstan on the coast of Issyk Kul Lake. It has been hosting guests for over ten years, impressing tourists from Asia, Europe, the United States, Russia, the Middle East and other places. The unique sand beach, pier, suitable for parking large boats, amazing green territory, and beautiful infrastructure are its competitive advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business foundational patterns during pandemic in the UK</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>• How many companies were incorporated during the pandemic? Did the number fall? How did the number change month by month? How was it in comparison to a previous couple of years? How did this trend differ across industries?
• Considering London as the centre of economic activity with the most significant number of companies registrations, did the pandemic affect the location of companies’ birth?
• How did the number differ across all possible SIC codes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment diffusion at the trading floor</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Individual Final course project in Network Analytics 📔 GitHub Repo of the Project contains the Jupyter notebook with both presentation and the code!
Background The compound of technologies we use to call &amp;lsquo;AI&amp;rsquo; promises to revolutionize many sectors. However, there is a substantial gap between what firms say they do with AI and what they actually do with it [1]. Several factors could account for such a gap: the adoption of AI tools is costly since it tends to jeopardize an incumbent&amp;rsquo;s operations [2]; there is a shortage of human capital trained in the area of AI [3]; developing AI applcations may require businesses to cope with ethical/societal implications [4, 5] and regulatory issues [6].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Google Pixel 6 vs Iphone 12 Pro marketing campaigns</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Enjoy the presentation and here is the corresponding 📂 Github Repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes Tic-Toc videos popular?</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>📂 Github Repo has the corresponding Jupyter notebook and beautiful report 😋.
The tasks:
to familiarize with the TikTok Trending Videos dataset to use Python to analyze the above-mentioned dataset and produce three statistical charts that complement an article for the printed version of the New York Times on &amp;lsquo;what makes TikTok&amp;rsquo; videos (super-)popular to produce a companion document that — in plain English — describes and arguments the design choices behind the three statistical charts Results </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring IMDB actors network using NetworkX</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction to this group project (Github link)
This project sought to analyse a proportion of the actor network embedded in the American film industry. Data used in the network analysis was scraped from a list on IMDb titled ‘ 500 Top-Rated Features Since 2000’. The scope of this project includes only US movies released between 2000 and 2012, and the 10 main actors from each film. The Hollywood movie industry is characterized by short-term relationships based on collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My background</title>
      <link>https://sinkov.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinkov.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Making informed decisions, having alternative solutions to each problem, possesing reliable data – were the key factors of the well-being of an enterprise, based on my professional experience.
I graduated from one of Europe&amp;rsquo;s most comprehensive programmes in Logistics and Supply Chain Management, where I got my hands dirty by gaining experience in the department of innovations at the national railway operator and conducting research of the supply chain of a large frozen food producer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
